Guide to the Ford E. and Harriet R. Curtis Theatre Collection of New York Theatre Programs, 1857-present CTC.1966.05
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Ford E. and Harriet R. Curtis Theatre Collection of New York Theatre Programs
1857-present
CTC.1966.05
ULS Archives & Special Collections
156.0 linear feet (336 mss boxes)
The Ford E. and Harriet R. Curtis Theatre Collection contains tens of thousands of New York theatre programs from the 1850s to the present. They include productions that were performed on Broadway, Off-Broadway, and elsewhere in the state of New York. Sometimes newspaper clippings, marketing materials, and memorabilia related to the productions are stored with the programs.
Curtis, Ford E., 1896-1979
Curtis, Harriet R., d. 1971
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Previous Citation
Ford E. and Harriet R. Curtis Theatre Collection of New York Theatre Programs, 1857-present, CTC.1966.05, Curtis Theatre Collection, Special Collections Department, University of Pittsburgh
Accruals
The Curtis Collection has a subscription to the opening night programs of Broadway productions through Playbill. In addition to the subscription, donations are added to the collection every few months. These donations are typically from the general public. If you are interested in donating theatre programs to the collection, please contact the Special Collections Department staff.
Related Material
Ford E. and Harriet R. Curtis Theatre Collection of Performing Arts Posters (finding aid in-progress)
Ford E. and Harriet R. Curtis Theatre Collection of Performing Arts Photographs (finding aid in-progress)
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into two series.
Series I. New York City Theatre Programs, 1857-present
Series II. New York Theatre Programs, 1891-2003
Scope and Content Notes
This collection contains nineteenth and twentieth century theatre programs from both New York City and elsewhere in the state of New York. The New York City programs are located in Series I and are filed chronologically. The New York state programs are filed alphabetically by theatre title in Series II.
Please note that this collection does not represent all of the New York theatre programs in the Curtis Collection. There are many New York City programs prior to 1930 in our scrapbook collection.
History
The Ford E. and Harriet R. Curtis Theatre Collection contains a fantastic collection of New York theatre programs. Dr. Ford E. Curtis began teaching drama in the English department at the University of Pittsburgh in 1924. He and his wife, Harriet, were avid theatre goers. They would take frequent trips to New York City to see Broadway shows.
In 1950, Dr. Curtis started a subscription to the opening night programs through Playbill. He then began to file the programs along with corresponding reviews, photographs, and other clippings. After his retirement in 1961, he began to add to their personal collection of playbills and programs in the hopes of building a collection to donate to Pitt. He solicited the help of the New York Public Library's Theatre Collection. For a period of about twelve years the Curtis Collection received fifteen to twenty boxes of duplicates from the NYPL. These contained programs, scrapbooks, photographs, journals, and scripts. Thousands of items in this and other Curtis collections are stamped DUPL NYPL.
The materials that Dr. Curtis amassed -- his own collection, materials donated to him, and the Curtis Collection staff's current efforts to acquire additional programs -- help to document the history of theatre and the performing arts.
Clippings (Information artifacts); Performing arts--New York (State)--New York; Theater programs; Theater programs--New York (State); Theater programs--New York (State)--New York; Theater--New York (State); Theater--New York (State)--New York
- New York City Theatre Programs, 1857-present; I.
  Scope and Content Notes
  This series is composed of all the Curtis Collection's theatre programs from New York City. The series is separated into two series. The first being Broadway theatre programs and the second compiles Off-Broadway and the other boroughs of New York City.
  - Broadway, 1857-present; 1.
    The Broadway programs collection is broken into three organizational schemes. There are two folders of programs without dates; these are filed alphabetically. The nineteenth century and early twentieth century programs are filed by the date printed in the program. From 1943 to the current Broadway season, all the programs of a specific production's run are filed chronologically by it's opening night date. These dates are usually printed in the program. When they are not, staff use Theatre World and the Internet Broadway Database to determine a production's opening night. Finally, there is a small amount of programs without dates. These are primarily nineteenth century programs and they are filed at the start of the series alphabetically by their title.
    Supplementary to the programs, there are newspaper clippings, marketing materials, and memorabilia related to productions in the folders. These materials are available for the programs dating from the mid 1950s through the mid 1980s.
    - Broadway theatre programs - Undated (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
    - Broadway theatre programs, 1857 (Folder 3)
    - Broadway theatre programs, 1866-1889 (Folder 4)
    - Broadway theatre programs, 1890-1899 (Box 2-3)
    - Broadway theatre programs, 1900-1910 (Box 4-13)
    - Broadway theatre programs, 1911-1920 (Box 14-28)
    - Broadway theatre programs, 1921-1930 (Box 29-49)
    - Broadway theatre programs, 1931-1942 (Box 50-101)
    - Broadway theatre programs - Oklahoma, March 31, 1943 (Box 102)
    - Broadway theatre programs, 1943-1949 (Box 103-127)
    - Broadway theatre programs - South Pacific, April 7, 1949 (Box 128)
    - Broadway theatre programs, 1949-1975 (Box 129-208)
    - Broadway theatre programs - Chorus Line, July 25, 1975 (Box 209)
    - Broadway theatre programs, 1975-1987 (Box 210-243)
    - Broadway theatre programs - Les Misérables, March 12, 1987 (Box 244)
    - Broadway theatre programs, 1987-2016 (Box 245-288)
  - Off-Broadway, 1875-present; 2.
    The Off-Broadway programs are filed chronologically by the date of the program. When there were no dates printed on the programs, the productions were researched to find out when the opening night was and filed under that date. The programs which we found no opening night information for are arranged in alphabetical order by the name of the venue they were performed at. Also filed in with the Off-Broadway materials were a small amount of programs from other New York City boroughs.
    - Off-Broadway theatre programs, 1875-1949 (Box 1-6)
    - Off-Broadway theatre programs, 1950-1969 (Box 7-20)
    - Off-Broadway theatre programs, 1970-1979 (Box 21-27)
    - Off-Broadway theatre programs, 1980-present (Box 28-37)
    - Off-Broadway theatre programs - Undated (Box 38-40)
- New York State Theatre Programs, 1891-2003; II.
  The theatre programs in this series are from the state of New York. Each file is labeled with the name of the theatre and the name of the city or town it is in. Also listed is the total number of folders for each theatre. The files are arranged alphabetically by the theatre's name. The boxes are not listed or numbered because these numbers change with new donations.
  - Academy Theatre - Woodmere, 1934; 1.0 folder
  - Adirondack Players - Saranac Lake, 1960; 1.0 folder
    Also includes the Adirondack Playhouse.
  - Alden Theatre - Jamaica, June 29, 1936; 1.0 folder
  - American Youth Theatre Guild - New Rochelle, 1.0 folder
  - Arena Theatre - Rochester, 1951-1952; 1.0 folder
  - Artpark Theater - Lewiston, 1974-1996; 1.0 folder
  - Astor Theatre - Syracuse, 1953; 1.0 folder
  - Auditorium Theatre - Rochester, 1931-1964; 1.0 folder
    Also includes the Auditorium Permanent Players.
  - Baker Theatre - Rochester, January 1899; 1.0 folder
  - Banbox Players - Hempstead, 1.0 folder
  - Bard Theatre - Red Hook, December 1936; 1.0 folder
  - Barnstormers Theatre - Cragsmoor
    See Also
    Cragsmoor Players and Cragsmoor Theatre
  - Barn Playhouse - Bolton Landing, 1.0 folder
  - Bay Street Theatre - Sag Harbor, 2003; 1.0 folder
  - Beechwood Theatre - Ossining, 1928-1932; 1.0 folder
  - Beechwood Players - Scarborough, 1931-1952; 1.0 folder
  - Biltmore Theatre - Mount Vernon, 1.0 folder
  - Blythewood Summer Theatre - Chestertown, 1.0 folder
  - Bridgeport Playhouse - Bridgeport, 1940-1948; 1.0 folder
  - Brighton Theatre - Brighton Beach, 1930-1948; 1.0 folder
  - Bristol Valley Playhouse - Bristol, August 1966; 1.0 folder
  - Broadway Theatre - Nyack, 1932; 1.0 folder
  - Bronxville Auditorium - Bronxville, 1930-1936; 1.0 folder
  - Capital Theatre - Albany, 1929-1933; 1.0 folder
  - Capri Theatre - Atlantic Beach, 1956-1958; 1.0 folder
  - Carlton Theatre - Jamaica, 1.0 folder
  - Castle Theatre - Long Beach, 1930-1933; 1.0 folder
  - Catholic Theatre of Rochester, May 1960; 1.0 folder
  - Cecilwood Theatre - Fishkill, 1949-1974; 1.0 linear feet
  - Cedarhurst Playhouse - Cedarhurst, 1935-1945; 1.0 folder
  - Celoron Theatre - Jamestown, 1.0 folder
  - Central Theatre - Cedarhurst, 1941; 1.0 folder
  - Chapel Theatre - Great Neck, 1938-1947; 1.0 folder
  - Chamberlain Brown Players - Mount Vernon, 1932; 1.0 folder
  - Chappaqua Drama Group - Chappaqua, 1985-1987; 1.0 folder
  - Chautauqua Conservatory Theater - Chautauqua, 1988; 1.0 folder
  - Civic Players - Schenectady, January 1948; 1.0 folder
  - Clare Tree Major Children's Theatre - Chautauqua, 1939; 1.0 folder
  - Cliff Theatre - Sea Cliff, 1.0 folder
  - Coach House Players - Kingston, 1960-1965; 1.0 folder
  - Collingwood Opera House - Poughkeepsie, 1895-1898; 3.0 folders
  - Colonial Theatre - Utica, 1916; 1.0 folder
  - Colonie Summer Theatre - Latham, 1961-1963; 1.0 folder
  - Cook Opera House - Rochester, 1911; 1.0 folder
  - Corinthian Theatre - Rochester, November 1910; 1.0 folder
  - Corning Summer Theatre - Corning, 1957-1969; 1.0 folder
  - Cortland Repertory Theatre - Cortland, 1982; 1.0 folder
  - County Center Theatre - White Plains, 1931-1952; 1.0 folder
  - Country Playhouse - Fayetteville, 1949-1961; 1.0 folder
  - Country Theatre - East Islip, 1.0 folder
  - Country Theatre - Suffern, 1933-1947; 1.0 folder
  - Cragsmoor Theatre - Cragsmoor, 1941-1949; 1.0 folder
    Also includes Cragsmoor Players
    See Barnstormers Theatre.
  - Crandell Summer Theatre - Chatham, 1949; 1.0 folder
  - Crest Theatre - Long Beach, 1947-1949; 1.0 folder
  - Croton River Playhouse - Croton-on-Hudson, 1.0 folder
  - Dewitt Theatre - Syracuse, 1931; 1.0 folder
  - Drama Festival - Woodmere, July 1934; 1.0 folder
  - Drew Theatre - East Hampton, 1.0 folder
    See John Drew Theatre
  - Duke's Oak Theatre - Cooperstown, 1936-1938; 1.0 folder
  - East Hampton Drama Festival, July 1941; 1.0 folder
  - Eastman Theatre - Rochester, 1928-1933; 1.0 folder
  - Embassy Theatre - Port Chester, September 1937; 1.0 folder
  - Empire Theatre - Albany, January 1900; 1.0 folder
  - Empire Theatre - Glen Falls, 1.0 folder
  - Empire Theatre - Syracuse, 1916-1950; 1.0 folder
  - Empire State Music Festival - Ellenville, July 1956; 1.0 folder
  - Erie Theatre - Schenectady, 1947; 1.0 folder
  - Erlanger Theatre - Buffalo, 1928-1954; 3.0 folders
  - Essex Players - Essex, 1.0 folder
  - Famous Artists Playhouse - Syracuse, 1966-1971; 1.0 folder
  - Finger Lakes Drama Festival - Ithaca, 1947-1948; 1.0 folder
  - Fisher Theatre - Seneca Falls, December 1916; 1.0 folder
  - Fox Playhouse - Great Neck, 1929-1931; 1.0 folder
  - Freeport Theatre - Freeport, 1928-1929; 1.0 folder
  - Gateway Playhouse - Bellport, June 1968; 1.0 folder
  - Goode Theatre - Clinton Hollow, 1.0 folder
    Includes Reginald Goode Theatre programs.
  - Great Neck Playhouse - Great Neck, 1927-1932; 1.0 folder
  - Greenbush Theatre - Blauvelt, 1940-1950; 1.0 folder
  - Griswold Opera House - Troy, January 1900; 1.0 folder
  - Hampton Summer Theatre - Bridgehampton, 1940-1947; 1.0 folder
  - Hamptons Theatre - Southampton, 1937; 1.0 folder
    Includes program starring the Southampton Players.
  - Harmanus Bleecker Hall - Albany, 1912-1938; 1.0 folder
  - Hempstead Art Theatre - Hempstead, 1946; 1.0 folder
  - Hendrick Hudson Theatre - Hudson, June 1949; 1.0 folder
  - Highland New Paltz Summer Theatre - Highland, August 1948; 1.0 folder
  - Hudson Theatre - Schenectady, 1927-1928; 1.0 folder
  - Hyde Park Playhouse - Hyde Park, 1956-1962; 1.0 folder
  - International Theatre - Niagara Falls, 1914; 1.0 folder
  - Jacoby Playhouse - Cedarhurst, 1944; 1.0 folder
  - John Drew Theatre - East Hampton, 1940-1983; 4.0 folders
    See also the Drew Theatre.
    Also includes programs from the John Drew Theatre of Guild Hall.
  - Jones Beach Marine Theatre - Wantagh, 1954-1975; 1.0 folder
  - Keith's Theatre - Syracuse, 1923-1950; 1.0 folder
  - Kleinhans Auditorium - Buffalo, 1972; 1.0 folder
    Also listed as Kleinhans Music Hall.
  - KRNT Radio Theatre - Utica, November 1957; 1.0 folder
  - Lake George Playhouse - Lake George, 1947-1949; 1.0 folder
  - Lake Luzerne Playhouse - Lake Luzerne, 1.0 folder
  - Lake Mahopac Playhouse - Lake Mahopac, 1939; 1.0 folder
  - Lake Placid Playhouse - Lake Placid, 1.0 folder
  - Lake Shore Playhouse - Derby, 1947-1950; 1.0 folder
  - Lakeside Theatre - Lake Placid, 1938; 1.0 folder
  - League Theatre - Flushing, 1.0 folder
  - Liberty Theatre - Camp Upton
  - Little Theatre - Jamestown, 1.0 folder
  - Lyceum Theatre - Elmira, 1922; 1.0 folder
  - Lyceum Theatre - Rochester, 1902-1932; 1.0 folder
  - Lyceum Theatre - Troy, 1918-1919; 1.0 folder
  - Lyric Circus Light Opera - Skaneateles, 1959; 1.0 folder
  - Lyric Circus Light Opera - Syracuse, 1960; 1.0 folder
  - Majestic Theatre - Buffalo, 1920-1925; 1.0 folder
  - Majestic Theatre - Elmira, 1927-1929; 1.0 folder
  - Majestic Theatre - Utica, 1.0 folder
  - Malden Bridge Playhouse - Malden Bridge, 1947-1950; 1.0 folder
  - Mamaroneck Playhouse - Mamaroneck, 1927; 1.0 folder
  - Manor Theatre - Pelham Manor, 1.0 folder
  - Maverick Theatre - Woodstock, 1933-1934; 1.0 folder
  - Millbrook Theatre - Millbrook, 1938; 1.0 folder
  - Millpond Playhouse - Roslyn, 1940; 1.0 folder
  - Mineola Theatre - Mineola, 1963-1968; 1.0 folder
  - Mirror Players - Buffalo, 1.0 folder
  - Mozart Players - Elmira, 1915; 1.0 folder
  - Music Theatre - Westchester, 1.0 folder
  - Nell Gwyn Theatre - Malden Bridge, 1934; 1.0 folder
  - New Rochelle Playhouse - New Rochelle, 1.0 folder
  - New Rochelle Theatre - New Rochelle, 1906-1929; 1.0 folder
  - North Shore Summer Theatre - Whitestone, 1935; 1.0 folder
  - Old Carriage House Players - Lake Ronkonkoma, July 1935; 1.0 folder
  - Old Town Theatre - Smithtown Branch, 1946-1949; 1.0 folder
  - Oneida Area Arts Council - Smithtown Branch, November 1970; 1.0 folder
  - Opera House - Glen Falls, August 1891; 1.0 folder
  - Orange County Playhouse - Westtown, 1947; 1.0 folder
  - Palace Theatre - White Plains, 1.0 folder
  - Pauls Players - Swan Lake, July 1938; 1.0 folder
  - Pine Bush Theatre - Pine Bush, July 1950; 1.0 folder
  - Pittsford Town Hall - Pittsford, 1946-1951; 1.0 folder
  - Players Company - Jamaica, May 1953; 1.0 folder
  - Players Company - Manhasset, 1946; 1.0 folder
  - Playhouse at the Cross Streams - Hopewell Junction, October 17, 1926; 1.0 folder
  - Playhouse - Lawrence, 1.0 folder
  - Playhouse Theatre - Cedarhurst, 1934; 1.0 folder
  - Playhouse - Albany, 1946-1950; 1.0 folder
  - Princess Theatre - New Rochelle, 1.0 folder
  - Proctor's Theatre - Schenectady, 1.0 folder
  - Putnam County Playhouse - Mahopac, 1946-1949; 1.0 folder
  - Queensboro Theatre - Elmhurst, 1.0 folder
  - Rand's Opera House - Troy, November 1911; 1.0 folder
  - Red Barn Theatre - Locust Valley, 1934-1950; 1.0 folder
  - Red Men's Hall - New Salem, May 1932; 1.0 folder
  - Redpath Chautauqua - White Plains, 1932; 1.0 folder
  - Reginald Goode Theatre - Clinton Hallow, 1.0 folder
    See Goode Theatre.
  - Ridgeway Theatre - White Plains, 1940-1941; 2.0 folder
  - Riverhead Summer Theatre - Riverhead, 1949; 1.0 folder
  - Riverside Shakespeare Company, 1984; 1.0 folder
  - RKO Theatre - White Plains, December 1953; 1.0 folder
  - Rochester Civic Theatre - Rochester, 1959-1969; 1.0 folder
    Also includes programs by the Rochester Community Players.
  - Rockland Theatre - Nyack, 1942-1949; 1.0 folder
  - Rockland County Circle Theatre - Orangeburg, September 1950; 1.0 folder
  - Rockridge Theatre - Carmel, 1938; 1.0 folder
  - Rockwood Hall Theatre - North Tarrytown, 1939; 1.0 folder
  - Roosevelt Theatre - Beacon, 1947; 1.0 folder
  - Rosedale Playhouse - Rosedale, 1941; 1.0 folder
  - Sacandaga Theatre - Northville, 1.0 folder
  - Sail Loft Theatre - Germantown, 1947; 1.0 folder
  - Saint Patrick's Institute Hall - Albany, February 1931; 1.0 folder
    Includes program from the St. Patrick's Players.
  - Salt City Playhouse - Syracuse, 1.0 folder
  - Sayville Playhouse - Sayville, 1944; 1.0 folder
  - Scarsdale Theatre - Scarsdale, 1942; 1.0 folder
  - Schenectady Light Opera - Schenectady, 1953; 1.0 folder
  - Schroon Lake Summer Theatre - Schroon Lake, 1.0 folder
  - Sea Cliff Summer Theatre - Sea Cliff, 1947-1956; 1.0 folder
  - Shea's Court Street Theatre - Jamestown, 1927-1929; 1.0 folder
    Programs feature the Court Street Players.
  - Shelley Players - Albany, 1956; 1.0 folder
  - Shubert Teck Theater - Buffalo, 1931; 1.0 folder
  - Skaneateles Summer Theatre - Skaneateles, 1937-1950; 1.0 folder
  - Skouras Hempstead Theatre - Hempstead, August 1933
  - Southampton Cabaret Theatre - Southampton, 1969; 1.0 folder
  - Southampton Playhouse - Southampton, 1.0 folder
  - South Presbyterian Church - Dobbs Ferry, 1.0 folder
  - Spa Theatre - Saratoga Springs, 1938-1960; 2.0 folders
    Includes programs labeled the New Spa Theatre.
  - Star Theatre - Buffalo, 1896-1915; 1.0 folder
  - Starlight Theatre - Pawling, 1936-1950; 2.0 folders
  - Stone Theatre - Binghamton, January 1930; 1.0 folder
  - Strand Theatre - Albany, 1949; 1.0 folder
  - Strand Theatre - Elmira, December 1948; 1.0 folder
  - Strand Theatre - Syracuse, 1.0 folder
  - Stratton Summer Playhouse - Middletown, July 1947; 1.0 folder
  - Studio Arena Theatre - Buffalo, 1966-1983; 1.0 folder
  - Summer Theatre - Watkins Glen, 1948-1950; 1.0 folder
  - Summer Theatre - Southampton, June 1929; 1.0 folder
  - Sunnyside Players - Sunnyside, 1.0 folder
  - Syracuse Little Theatre - Syracuse, 1961; 1.0 folder
  - Tamarack Playhouse - Lake Pleasant, 1938-1946; 1.0 folder
  - Tappan Zee Playhouse - Nyack, 1958-1968; 2.0 folder
  - Temple Theatre - Rochester, 1929; 1.0 folder
  - Theatre East - Rochester, January 1967; 1.0 folder
  - Theatre Guild of Oceanside - Oceanside, 1963; 1.0 folder
  - Theatre of the Four Seasons - Roslyn, 1935; 1.0 folder
  - Thousand Island Playhouse - Alexandria Bay, 1947; 1.0 folder
  - Threshold Playhouse - Pleasantville, 1951; 1.0 folder
  - Tinkers Pond Theatre - Syosset, 1.0 folder
  - Tivoli Theatre - East Northport, July 1949; 1.0 folder
  - Tower Bell Theatre - Nyack, 1.0 folder
  - Town and Country Playhouse - Rochester, 1.0 folder
  - University Regent Theatre - Syracuse, 1952-1963; 1.0 folder
  - Urban Playhouse - Yonkers, 1.0 folder
  - Van Curler Theatre - Schenectady, 1.0 folder
  - Vivian Theatre - Whitestone, 1950; 1.0 folder
  - Warburton Theatre - Yonkers, 1920-1924; 1.0 folder
  - Washington Irving Theatre - North Terrytown, 1938; 1.0 folder
  - Washington Theatre - Dobbs Ferry, 1934; 1.0 folder
  - Wedgeway Theatre - Schenectady, 1929; 1.0 folder
    Several of the programs feature the Wilcox Players.
  - Westbury Music Fair - Westbury, 1959-1967; 1.0 folder
  - Westbury Theatre - Westbury, 1.0 folder
  - Westchester Broadway Theatre - Elmsford, 1.0 folder
  - Westchester County Center - White Plains, 1930-1939; 1.0 folder
  - Westchester County Playhouse - Dobbs Ferry, 1963; 1.0 folder
  - Westchester Playhouse - Mount Kisco, 1932-1957; 6.0 folders
  - Westchester Theatre - Mount Vernon, 1914-1932; 3.0 folders
  - Westhampton Playhouse - Westhampton Beach
  - White Plains Playhouse - White Plains, July 1946; 1.0 folder
  - Wieting Opera House - Syracuse, 1898-1930; 1.0 folder
  - Wilsker's Westchester Dinner Theatre, 1.0 folder
  - Woodstock Playhouse - Woodstock, 1938-1964; 1.0 folder
  - Yonkers Playhouse - Yonkers, February 1964; 1.0 folder